Guide to the Phillip Rhodes papers, 1957-2022 RL.01084
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Chamber and Solo Instrumental Works, 1961-2022; undated; 5
  - Partita for solo viola, 1978-1986; undated; 12
    - Scores with edits, general correspondence, notes, flyer, 1978-1986; undated (Box 8)
    - Ann Woodward, viola, 1978 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0057)
    - Edition Peters score, 1988 (Box 45)
  - Phoenix Resurgens, 2009
    - Piano part, 2009 (Box 45)
  - Quartet for violin, flute, cello, and harp, 1975-1990; undated; 13
    - Bowling Green State University New Music Festival, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, programs, flyers
    - Music sketches, 1975 (Box 32)
    - Full scores with markings, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Full score with markings, undated (Box 32)
      Includes complete parts for final movement
    - Speculum Musicae, 1975 September 28 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0025)
    - Unknown performers, 1975 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0050)
    - Edition Peters score, 1988 (Box 45)
    - Musical examples, 1975 (Box 48)
  - Reflections: Eight Fantasies for piano, 1976-1978; 14
    - Music sketches, full score, manuscript copy, 1976-1977 (Box 35)
    - Anne Mayer, piano, 1978 January 20 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0026)
    - Unknown performers, 1977 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0052)
    - Edition Peters score, 1985 (Box 45)
  - Shakespeare in Song for high voice, clarinet, and piano, 2000-2001; undated; 15
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 31)
    - Full score, correspondence, poetry drafts, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
    - Score for singer in C, circa 2000s (Box 45)
    - Come Away Death with notes, circa 2000s (Box 45)
  - String Trio for violin, viola, and cello, 1964-1974; 16
    - Music sketches and scores, 1964-1973 (Box 31)
      Includes original full score manuscript, master sheets, revised score and parts
    - Score and complete parts, 1974 (Box 8)
      Includes note from the composer
    - Alabama Woodwind Quintet; University of Alabama Symphony Orchestra (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0039)
    - American Music Awards series score, 1974 (Box 46)
    - Edition Peters score, 1974 (Box 46)
  - Suite No. 2 for Five Winds, 1961-1962; 17
    - Suite for Five Winds music sketches and parts, 1961 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, full scores and complete, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Duke Woodwind Quintet, with Alan Bone, 1964 April 21 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0041)
    - Score, 1962 (Box 48)
  - The Sweet Rivers Waltz, 2008; undated; 18
    - Music sketches, score, program notes, 2008; undated (Box 8)
  - Three Gershwin Settings for violin and piano, 2000; 19
    - Music sketches, full scores, violin part, 2000 (Box 32)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0063)
    - Score, circa 2000s (Box 46)
    - Violin part, circa 2000s (Box 46)
  - Three Pieces for solo cello, 1965-1968; 20
    - Music sketches and full score, 1968 (Box 34)
    - Original manuscript with vellum master sheets, 1965-1966 (Box 41)
    - Unknown performers, 1966 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0059)
  - Three pieces for violoncello solo, 1968
    - Edition Peters score, 1968 (Box 46)
  - Two Appalachian Settings for string quartet, 1998-2001; 21
    - Music sketches and full score, 2001 (Box 31)
    - Full score and complete parts, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence and notes, 2000 (Box 46)
    - Score and parts, 2000 (Box 46)
  - Visions of Remembrance for two sopranos and twelve instruments, 1978-1995; 22
    - Boston Chamber Ensemble, 1995 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, program notes, newspaper clippings
    - Mexico City Festival, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Norfolk Performance, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, 1978-1979 (Box 33)
    - Full scores, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      Includes Phillip Rhodes' personal scores for recording sessions
    - Full score and complete parts, 1979 (Box 32)
    - Full score original manuscript copy, 1978-1979 (Box 33)
    - Copy of Edition Peters score, 1981 (Box 46)
  - Wedding Song, A Blessing, 1990; 23
    - Recorded live at the United Church of Christ in Northfield, MN, 1990 September 2 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0013)
    - Unknown performers, 1990 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0043)
- Choral and Solo Vocal Works, 1961-2001; undated; 6
  Choral and Solo Vocal Works comprises music Rhodes wrote for choral ensemble or solo vocalist. Several choral works include a variety of ensemble accompaniments, such as percussion or wind quartet. Some choral works are written specifically for children's ensemble with Orff instrumentation, although most are for either mixed or women's chorus. Some works include correspondence, programs, and newspaper clippings. Most of the pieces include music sketches, drafts, choral scores, full scores, original manuscripts, and recordings. Some pieces include master sheets and proofs. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  - Ad Honorem Stravinsky for SATB, 1981-1986; 24
    - Music sketches, choral score, letter, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Edition Peters score, 1986 (Box 46)
  - Benediction Setting, 1973; 25
    - Music sketches and choral score, 1973 (Box 38)
    - Original manuscript, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Chorale and Organ Meditation, 1994-1997; 26
    - Music sketches, full scores, solo organ score, program, 1994-1995 (Box 39)
    - Revised score, 1997 (Box 46)
  - Christmas Cantata: On the Morning of Christ's Nativity for SATB, wind quartet, and harp, 1976-1998; 27
    - Brunelle, Philip correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - I Cantori New York performance, 1995 (Box 8)
      Correspondence, programs
    - Music sketches, vocal score, newspaper clipping, 1976; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Choral score excerpts, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Full score, 1976 (Box 40)
    - The Shepherds and Epilogue Edition Peters vocal score, 1978 (Box 46)
    - "On the Morning of Christ's Nativity" Edition Peters vocal score, 1978 (Box 46)
  - Dancing Songs for treble choir and Orff instrumentation (from Music for Children), 1984-1991; undated; 28
    - Drafts and proofs, 1991; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Composers Commissioning Program application materials, Full score, flyers, notes, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
    - Music sketches, 1984-1988; undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Proofs and publishing drafts, 1986-1988; undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Stevens Point Public Schools Honor Choirs and University of Wisconsin Percussion Ensemble, conducted by Judy Bond and Robert Rosen, 1985; 1979 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0069)
    - Score and teaching guide, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Dear Companion, 1977
    - Score, 1977 (Box 46)
    - Master copies, 1977 (Box 46)
  - Demonstration choral piece, 1970
    - Score, 1970 (Box 48)
  - Five Songs on Children's Poems for high voice and piano, 1972; 29
    - Full score, original manuscript, 1972 (Box 38)
    - Unknown performers, 1972 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0054)
    - Score, circa 1970s (Box 46)
  - Grenada, for solo voice, 1963; 30
    - Music sketches, 1963 (Box 35)
  - The Hour Draws Nigh for SATB and percussion, undated; 31
    - Choral score photocopy, undated (Box 9)
    - Score, undated (Box 46)
  - In Praise of Wisdom for SATB, trumpets, and trombones, 1982; 32
    - Music sketches, choral score with markings, original manuscript copy, 1982 (Box 38)
  - I Will Arise, 2006
    - Draft, 2006 (Box 46)
  - Kyrie for SSA, 1966-1967; 33
    - Full score, manuscript copy, 1966-1967 (Box 36)
    - Edition Peters score, 1967 (Box 46)
  - A Lullaby for the Nativity, 2012
    - Score, 2012 (Box 46)
    - Violin part, 2012 (Box 48)
  - Madrigal II, 1969
    - Score, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Mountain Songs for high voice and piano, 1976-1987; 35
    - Music sketches, full scores, 1976 (Box 36)
    - Margaret Brand, soprano; Anne Mayer, piano, 1987 November 6 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0027)
    - Edition Peters score, 1979 (Box 46)
  - Nets to Catch the Wind for SATB and percussion, 1985-1998; undated; 36
    - Gregg Smith Singers correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - Assorted correspondence and program, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, 1986 (Box 39)
    - Final drafts with edits, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Full score manuscript copy, choral scores, incomplete proofs, 1997-1998; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Collection of performances; includes Washington Singers, Oregon Repertory Singers, and Carleton Chamber Singers, undated (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0016)
    - Excerpt publication, undated (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0046)
    - Oregon Repertory Singers, conducted by Gilbert Seely, 1987 March (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0015)
    - Paul Hill Chorale and Washington Singers, conducted by Paul Hill, 1987 March 21 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0014)
    - Unknown performers, 1986 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0049)
    - From the Stone of John Booth score, 1997 (Box 46)
    - Edition Peters score, 1997 (Box 46)
  - Prayers from the Psalms for soprano, SATB, and organ, 1972-1975; 37
    - Bradley Hills correspondence, 1972 (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, full score, manuscript copy, master sheets, 1972; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, Bethesda, MD, 1973 February 3 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0030)
    - Carleton College Choir, conducted by William Wells, 1975 May (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0029)
    - Unknown performers, 1972 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0053)
    - Score, 1972 (Box 48)
  - Recollections of a Summer Past for tenor and piano, 1962; 38
    - Music sketches and full score, 1962 (Box 38)
  - Three Appalachian Settings for SATB and violin, 2000; 39
    - Music sketches, full score, proofs with markings, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Score, 2000 (Box 46)
    - Cluck Ol' Hen score, 2000 (Box 46)
    - Pretty Saro original manuscript, 2000-2013 (Box 46)
  - Three French Songs for SATB, 1961-2001; 40
    - Music sketches, choral score, original manuscript, 1961-2001 (Box 38)
    - Louisville Chamber Singers, conducted by Brench Boden, 1971 February (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0032)
    - Unknown performers, 1961 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0058)
    - Scores, 1968; 2001 (Box 47)
  - Three Kentucky Songs for treble choir and piano, 1973; 41
    - Music sketches, full score, master sheets, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Three Scenes for Voice and Piano, 1964-1968; 42
    - Full scores, original manuscript, 1964-1966 (Box 36)
    - Lorraine Gorrell, mezzo-soprano; Janes Rhodes, piano, 1967 April 7 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0033)
    - Phyllis Bryn-Julson, soprano; John Metz, piano, 1968 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0034)
    - Unknown performers, 1965 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0066)
    - Unknown performers, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0044)
  - Untitled pieces, 1980s
    - Music sketches and notes, 1980s (Box 48)
  - The Virgin Mary's Lullaby for soprano, violin, and organ, 1993; 34
    - Music sketches and full scores, 1993 (Box 39)
      Includes alternate setting; Wedding Song, A Blessing for soprano, violin, and organ
    - Score, 1993 (Box 47)
  - Wind Songs for treble choir and Orff instrumentation (from Music for Children), 1979; 43
    - Full scores, correspondence, notes, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, 1979 (Box 36)
    - Score, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Wiiticisms and Lamentations from the Graveyard for SATB, 1972-1991; 44
    - Bowdoin College Choir Festival, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, full scores, proofs, 1972 (Box 40)
    - Edition Peters score, 1977 (Box 47)
- Operas and Oratorios, 1967-1998; undated; 7
  Operas and Oratorios consists of a variety of materials related to Rhodes' operatic works. Most of the pieces include music sketches, libretto drafts, revised scores, original manuscripts, piano-vocal scores, orchestral scores, and conductor's scores. Some pieces also include recordings, as well as correspondence and other administrative documents related to production and staging. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  - The Gentle Boy, 1979-1990; undated; 45
    - Correspondence and bills, 1981-1990; 3 folders (Box 9)
      Includes correspondence with Robert Driver
    - National Opera Association, 1986 (Box 9)
      Newsletter, programs, notes
    - Programs and newspaper review, 1982-1987 (Box 9)
    - Notebooks with assorted notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Libretto drafts and notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Orchestra parts with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Piano-vocal score photocopy, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - Chorus parts photocopies, undated (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, undated; 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Scenes I-VI revised orchestral score manuscripts, 1987; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Scenes III-VI orchestral scores, 1987; 2 folders (Box 20)
      Phillip Rhodes' copies with revisions
    - Scenes I-VI conductor's scores with markings, 1987; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Scenes I-II orchestral score with revisions, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Revised piano-vocal scores, 1987; 3 folders (Box 21)
      Includes Phillip Rhodes' copy with markings and original manuscript copy
    - Carleton College, 1982 April 2 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0010)
    - Florida State University Opera Theater, 1987 October (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0009)
    - Unknown performers, 1980; 1987 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0062)
  - Madrigal, 1967; 46
    - Two-piano vocal score, full scores, music sketches, 1967 (Box 13)
      Includes manscript copy with edits and conductor's marked score
    - Full score and complete parts, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Score, 1967 (Box 48)
  - The Magic Pipe, 1990-1998; undated; 47
    - Administrative documents, 1990-1992 (Box 9)
      Correspondence, memos, programs, budgets
    - Indiana University performance, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Program notes and drafts, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence and notes for concert program and video-taping, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Libretto drafts and notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Two-piano vocal score, undated (Box 42)
    - Complete libretto, Scene V fiddle part, undated (Box 42)
    - Music sketches, undated; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Orchestral score original manuscript with revisions, undated (Box 29)
    - Orchestral score original manuscript with revisions, undated (Box 30)
    - Carleton College Music Department and Chamber Singers, conducted by William Wells, 1991 April (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0006)
    - Unknown performers, 1990 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0042)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 12, Videotape RL01084-VHS-0001)
    - Score, 1990-1991 (Box 47)
  - Odysseus, 1971-1977; undated; 48
    - Scenario, full libretto, biographical profiles, undated (Box 42)
    - Music sketches and orchestral scores, 1974 (Box 28)
    - Revised orchestral score manuscript, 1971-1977 (Box 28)
    - Two scenes from proposed opera, recorded live in Louisville, KY, 1973 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0007)
    - Orchestral scores, 1974-1977 (Box 47)
    - Libretto text (final version), 1974-1977 (Box 47)
    - Clippings, 1974 (Box 47)
    - Opera package material, 1974 (Box 47)
    - Two scenes and notes, 1974 (Box 48)
  - From "Paradise Lost", 1971-1972; undated; 49
    - Program and notes, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1971-1972 (Box 42)
    - Bills and performance expenses, 1971-1972 (Box 42)
    - Libretto notes and drafts, undated (Box 17)
    - Music sketches, undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Music sketches on piano reduction by Jane Rhodes, undated (Box 17)
    - Acts I-II orchestral score original manuscript, undated; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Act III orchestral score original manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - Acts I-II conductor's scores, undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Acts I-III piano-vocal score original manuscripts, undated; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Acts I-II piano-vocal scores with Phillip Rhodes' notes and fingerings, undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Louisville Orchestra and Chorus, conducted by Jorge Mester, 1972 May 13 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0008)
    - Unknown performers, 1972 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0067)
    - Xerox of text from program, 1972 (Box 47)
    - Act I score, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
    - Act II score, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
    - Act III score, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
- Orchestral and Wind Ensemble Works, 1962-2001; undated; 8
  Orchestral and Wind Ensemble Works comprises music Rhodes wrote for larger orchestral ensemble or concert band. Most of the pieces include recordings, music sketches, full scores, revised scores, original manuscripts, and conductor's scores. Some pieces include piano reductions, master sheets, complete parts, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and other publicity materials. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  - About Faces, A Ballet for chamber orchestra, 1970; undated; 50
    - Production photographs, undated (Box 42)
    - Music sketches, orchcestral score, 1970 (Box 25)
    - Full score manuscript copy and Jane Rhodes' piano reduction drafts, 1970 (Box 42)
    - Kentucky Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Yoav Talmi, 1970 September 10 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0020)
  - Anniversary Waltz for Pat and Peter, 1970; 51
    - Music sketch, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Berea Country Dancers Arrangements, undated; 52
    - Full score and program notes, undated (Box 28)
  - Ceremonial Fanfare and Chorale, 1977; 53
    - Full score, complete parts, music sketches, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Concerto for Bluegrass Band and Orchestra, 1974-1989; undated; 54
    - Appalachian State University Exhibit, 1986-1989 (Box 42)
      Correspondence, newspaper clipping
    - Recording correspondence and notes, 1981 (Box 42)
    - Music sketches, 1974 (Box 27)
    - Piano reduction score drafts, undated (Box 26)
    - Conductor's score and proofs, 1974 (Box 26)
    - Early version: Bluegrass Festival Suite; McLain Family Band with the Asheville Symphony Orchestra (NC), undated (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0024)
    - Early version: Bluegrass Festival Suite; McLain Family Band with the Louisville Orchestra, conducted by Jorge Mester, undated (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0023)
    - Notes, 1970s (Box 48)
  - Cosmic Fantasies for young band, 1983-1999; undated; 55
    - Full scores with edits, 1983-1985; undated (Box 42)
      Includes correspondence, programs, program notes
    - Music sketches, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Full score and revised full score, 1983-1999 (Box 22)
    - Full score original manuscript copy, undated (Box 22)
    - Unknown performers, 1983 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0064)
  - The Devil's Advocate for concert band, 1972-1995; undated; 56
    - Duke University Commission, 1972-1974 (Box 42)
    - Duke University Wind Symphony concert, 1995 (Box 42)
    - Music sketches, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Full score, 1972-1974 (Box 42)
    - Conductor's score with markings, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Uncorrected master sheets, undated (Box 23)
    - Complete parts, undated (Box 23)
    - Indiana University Concert Band, conducted by Ray Cramer, 1977 April 12 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0001)
    - University of Miami Wind Ensemble, conducted by Frederick Fennell, 1978 March 23 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0002)
    - Unknown performers, 1972 (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0065)
  - Divertimento for small orchestra, 1971-1975; 57
    - St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, 1974-1975 (Box 42)
    - Music sketches and orchestral scores, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score original manuscript copy, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Edition Peters score, 1988 (Box 47)
  - Four Movements for chamber orchestra, 1962-1964; 58
    - Orchestral score and complete parts, 1962 (Box 25)
    - Music sketches and orchestral score original manuscript, 1962 (Box 25)
    - Alabama Woodwind Quintet; University of Alabama Symphony Orchestra, 1964 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0039)
    - Duke Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Alan Bone; University of Louisville Orchestra, conducted by James Livingston (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0040)
    - Score copy, 1962 (Box 47)
  - The Lament of Michal for soprano and orchestra, 1970-1980; 59
    - Publicity materials, 1970 (Box 42)
      Newspaper clippings, reviews, program, program notes
    - Music sketches, orchestral score original manuscript photocopy, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Atlanta Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Robert Shaw; Phyllis Bryn-Julson, soprano, 1980 February 16 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0018)
    - Louisville Orchestra, conducted by Jorge Mester; Phyllis Bryn-Julson, soprano, 1970 April 4 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0019)
    - Unknown performers, 1970 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0051)
  - March Parody for concert band, 2000-2001; 60
    - Full score, 2000-2001 (Box 22)
    - Music revisions, 2000 (Box 22)
    - Unknown performers, 2001 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0061)
  - McLain Family Band Arrangements, 1974-1981; undated; 61
    - Press book, 1974 (Box 42)
      Includes newspaper clippings, programs, biographical information
    - Orchestral score original manuscripts, undated; 3 folders (Box 28)
      Includes: Back up and Push, Bound for Gloryland, Come on out Tonight, High Hopes, Live it up Honey, Movin' on to Higher Ground, On the Road, One Step at a Time, Silver Creek, You Sing for me
    - Carleton College Orchestra, conducted by Jeremy Balmuth, 1981 March 28-29 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0005)
  - Reels and Reveries for orchestra, 1991-1994; undated; 62
    - Music sketches, 1991 (Box 27)
    - Orchestral score with revisions, 1992 (Box 42)
    - Unmarked orchestral score, 1994 (Box 42)
    - Orchestral score manuscript copy with edits, undated (Box 27)
    - Revised orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 27)
    - Personal score with notes, 1990-1991 (Box 47)
    - Edition Peters score, 1994 (Box 47)
    - Event program, 1992 (Box 47)
    - Addendum notes, 1991 (Box 48)
  - Remembrance for concert band, 1966-1969; 63
    - Music sketches, 1966 (Box 23)
    - Conductor's score, 1966-1967 (Box 41)
    - Full score original manuscript copy, 1966-1967 (Box 41)
    - Indiana University Concert Band, conducted by Robert Glidden, 1969 April 27; May 17 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0003)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 12, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0068)
    - Score, 1966-1967 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Sarabande for chamber orchestra, 1986-1990s
    - Score copy and notes, 1986-1990s (Box 47)
  - Someone to Watch Over Me, 2013
    - Original manuscript for orchestral version, 2013 (Box 47)
  - A Tango Fantasy for chamber orchestra, 1985-2014; undated; 64
    - Music sketches and Phillip Rhode's orchestral score with markings, undated (Box 24)
    - Orchestral score original manuscript copy with edits, undated (Box 24)
      Includes correspondence and program notes
    - Original version score, 1985 (Box 47)
    - Revised version score, 2014 (Box 47)
    - Notes, 2014 (Box 47)
    - Draft and notes, 1988 (Box 48)
  - Three Bs for Orchestra, 1971-1972; 65
    - Music sketches, orchestral score, 1971 (Box 41)
    - Louisville-Jefferson County Youth Orchestra, conducted by Rubin Scher, 1972 April (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0004)
  - Three Pieces for Concert Band, 1967-1992; 66
    - National Band Association Commission, 1967-1968 (Box 42)
    - Full score, master sheets, music sketches, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Cass Technical High School Band, conducted by Phillip Rhodes, 1970 April 11 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0004)
    - Miami University Wind Ensemble, conducted by Gary A. Speck, 1992 May 3 (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0060)
  - Sarabande and Tango Fantasy, 1989; 67
    - Carleton College, conducted by Janine Wager, 1989 May (Box 11, Audio-cd RL01084-CD-0017)
  - Unfinished orchestra piece, 1970s
    - Notes, 1970s (Box 48)